Amman Abua

Abuja, FCT, Nigeria.

+2348068545361 | <u>ammanabua@gmail.com</u>

www.ammanabua.com | www.linkedin.com/in/amman-abua | www.github.com/ammanabua

SUMMARY

A passionate and committed web developer with about 3 years professional experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C++, Python, JavaScript

Databases: SQL, MS Access, MongoDB

Tools: VSCode, Git, JEST, cli

Others: Strong knowledge of the software development lifecycle, React, Nodejs,

Express, Neo4J, WordPress.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Manyactive App Ltd

Remote

Software Developer (Part-time)

August 2021- November 2021

- o Built dashboard user interface using React and NextJs
- o Consumed APIs built in TypeScript/Nodejs to facilitate functionality of web applications.
- o Collaborated with product designers to improve the user interface of our products.
- Refactored backend codes to improve functionality, readability and efficiency.

Media Digest Limited

Abuja, Nigeria

Executive Assistant

January 2020 - December 2021

- o Designed and developed websites for business clients
- o Led a 5-person team to achieve a 30% increase in traffic on our website
- o Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure the smooth operation of company projects.

• Twin Crown Studios Ltd.

Abuja, Nigeria

3D Designer & Modeller

February 2017 - December 2017

- Designed and developed low poly 2D & 3D models for animation in mobile games using Blender and Unreal Engine.
- o Designed and developed landing pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Bootstrap

EDUCATION

Nile University of Nigeria, F.C.T. Abuja, Nigeria

September 2022

Post Graduate Diploma in Computer Science

Afe Babalola University, Ado-Ekiti, Nigeria

October 2016

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical/Electronics

Online Courses and Certifications: Responsive Web Design, JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, Web Developer Bootcamp

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Soft Skills: teamwork, clear communication, leadership, critical thinking.
- Interests: reading, traveling, playing basketball, painting, playing guitar

References available on request.